Guide to the George Mason University Libraries records, 1949-2008
George Mason University Libraries
- Series 10: Photographs, audiovisual, artifacts 1967-1999
  - Subseries 10.1: Photographs, 1967-1990
    Includes photographs, contacts sheets, negatives, and slides featuring library staff, Fenwick Library and the Johnson Center buildings.
    - Special Collections and Archives, 1980 September 1 (Box 193, Folder 1)
    - Arnold and Marge Sundgaard, Alan Cook, Joanne Johnson, John O'Connor, 1980 April-May (Box 193, Folder 2)
    - Special Collections, photographs of office in the 80s, 1980s (Box 193, Folder 3)
    - Senator William Scott in Special Collections and Archives, 1979 (Box 193, Folder 4)
    - Special Collections staff, 1980s? (Box 193, Folder 5)
    - Special Collections space, 1980s (Box 193, Folder 6)
    - Staff (Box 194, Folder 1)
    - Library, 1972 October 30 (Box 194, Folder 2)
      Contact sheet and negatives
    - Academic affairs dinner at Gunston Hall, 1981 November 14 (Box 194, Folder 3)
    - Alumni dinner, 1981 May 16 (Box 194, Folder 4)
    - Fenwick Library, 1968 (Box 194, Folder 5)
    - Fenwick Library, circa 1978 (Box 194, Folder 6)
      Negatives
    - Fenwick Library, circa 1978 (Box 194, Folder 7)
      Slides
    - Dedication of Fenwick Library, 1967 December 15 (Box 194, Folder 8)
      Photographs, program, copies of newspaper articles
    - Dedication of Fenwick Library, 1967 December 15 (Box 194, Folder 9)
    - Library interior, 1972 (Box 194, Folder 10)
    - Future Fenwick Library, undated (Box 194, Folder 11)
      Photographs of library model
    - Fenwick Library 1982 renovation (Box 194, Folder 12)
    - Fenwick wing B, 1970s (Box 194, Folder 13)
    - Staff photographs, 1988-1990 (Box 194, Folder 14)
      Photograph album pages removed from binder, 1 of 2
    - Staff photographs, 1988-1990 (Box 194, Folder 15)
      Photograph album pages removed from binder, 2 of 2
    - Graduation main campus, 1981 May 16 (Box 194, Folder 16)
      Prints and negatives
    - McDermott, Shindler, Veenstra, 1977 July 13 (Box 194, Folder 17)
    - Slides from the Snowden Conkey talk, 1979 June 19 (Box 194, Folder 18)
    - Photographs for Special Collections scrapbook, undated (Box 194, Folder 19)
    - Johnson Center, undated (Box 195, Folder 1)
      Oversize
  - Subseries 10.2: Audiovisual, 1979-1999
    Includes VHS and U-matic videocassette tapes, an audio cassette tape, a reel to reel tape and a 45rpm record featuring library related seminars, lectures, and meetings as well as information on library technology.
    - "Television's greatest hits - Valentine!", 1999 (Box 196, Folder 2)
      45 rpm record
    - The 3M self check system: a revolution in library materials flow management, 1994 (Box 196, Folder 3)
      VHS
    - Carlos Fuentes, visiting Robinson Professor, 1988 June 6 (Box 211, Folder 1)
      Letter from Fuentes to Iris Knell
    - Carlos Fuentes lecture, inaugural lecture on Latin America, 1988 January 28 (Box 211)
      VHS, 51:37
    - Carlos Fuentes lecture, the social and economic crisis in Latin America, 1988 February 4 (Box 211)
    - Carlos Fuentes lecture, Latin America and the United States, 1988 February 11 (Box 211)
      VHS, 50:41
    - Carlos Fuentes lecture, Latin America as a polycultural area, the Mediterranean and medieval traditions, 1988 February 18 (Box 211)
      VHS, 56:00
    - Carlos Fuentes lecture, the Hispanic tradition, 1988 February 25 (Box 211)
      VHS, 1:10:39
    - Carlos Fuentes lecture, the Indian tradition: the Aztecs of Mexico, 1988 March 3 (Box 211)
      VHS, 59:45
    - Carlos Fuentes lecture, the Renaissance tradition: More, Machiavelli, and Erasmus, 1988 March 10 (Box 211)
      VHS, 61:44
    - Carlos Fuentes lecture, conquest and counterconquest: the search for a name and voice, 1988 March 24 (Box 211)
      VHS, 58:45
    - Carlos Fuentes lecture, the political experience of independence, 1988 March 31 (Box 211)
    - Carlos Fuentes lecture, the political experience of independence, 1988 March 31 (Box 211)
    - Carlos Fuentes lecture, the cultural experience of independence, 1988 April 7 (Box 211)
      VHS, 60:47
    - Carlos Fuentes lecture, the crucible of fiction, 1988 April 14 (Box 211)
      VHS, 61:27
    - Carlos Fuentes lecture, Latin America faces the future, 1988 May 5 (Box 211)
      VHS, 64:10
    - Carlos Fuentes lecture, 1988 May 12 (Box 213)
    - Carlos Fuentes lecture, inaugural lecture on Latin America, 1988 January 28 (Box 212)
      U-matic, 51:37
    - Carlos Fuentes lecture, the social and economic crisis in Latin America, 1988 February 4 (Box 212)
      U-matic
    - Carlos Fuentes lecture, Latin America and the United States, 1988 February 11 (Box 212)
      U-matic, 50:41
    - Carlos Fuentes lecture, Latin America as a polycultural area, the Mediterranean and medieval traditions, 1988 February 18 (Box 212)
      U-matic, 56:00
    - Carlos Fuentes lecture, Latin America as a polycultural area, the Mediterranean and medieval traditions, 1988 February 18 (Box 212)
      3/4 inch DUB, 56:00
    - Carlos Fuentes lecture, the Hispanic tradition, 1988 February 25 (Box 212)
      U-matic, 1 of 2, 1:10:39
    - Carlos Fuentes lecture, the Hispanic tradition, 1988 February 25 (Box 212)
      U-matic, 2 of 2, 1:10:39
    - Carlos Fuentes lecture, the Indian tradition: the Aztecs of Mexico, 1988 March 3 (Box 212)
      U-matic, 59:45
    - Carlos Fuentes lecture, the Renaissance tradition: More, Machiavelli, and Erasmus, 1988 March 10 (Box 212)
      U-matic, 61:44
    - Carlos Fuentes lecture, conquest and counterconquest: the search for a name and voice, 1988 March 24 (Box 212)
      U-matic, 58:45
    - Carlos Fuentes lecture, the political experience of independence, 1988 March 31 (Box 212)
      U-matic, 1 of 2,
    - Carlos Fuentes lecture, the political experience of independence, 1988 March 31 (Box 212)
      U-matic, 2 of 2,
    - Carlos Fuentes lecture, the cultural experience of independence, 1988 April 7 (Box 212)
      U-matic, 60:47
    - Carlos Fuentes lecture, the crucible of fiction, 1988 April 14 (Box 212)
      U-matic, 61:27
    - Carlos Fuentes lecture, Latin America faces the future, 1988 May 5 (Box 212)
      U-matic, 1 of 2, 64:10
    - Carlos Fuentes lecture, Latin America faces the future, 1988 May 5 (Box 212)
      U-matic, 2 of 2, 64:10
    - Carlos Fuentes lecture, 1988 May 12 (Box 213)
    - Carlos Fuentes lecture, 1988 May 12 (Box 213)
    - Computer lab advanced support system (CLASS), undated (Box 196, Folder 4)
      2 VHS
    - EDUCOM '93 9345 tape 20 general session part one, 1993 (Box 196, Folder 5)
    - International conference on the electronic library, OCLC, undated (Box 196, Folder 6)
    - Introduction to Fenwick Library, 1989 August (Box 197, Folder 1)
    - The library and the humanities seminar, 1980 April 21 (Box 197, Folder 2)
      Cassette tape and evaluation narrative
    - Library seminar, Dr. Pat Lee, Mr. Winston Tabb, Dr. Anthony Welch, 1979 September 8 (Box 197, Folder 3)
      7" reel to reel
    - Networked information and the scholar teleconference, 1994 October 28 (Box 197, Folder 4)
    - New media centers, collaboration for innovation, undated (Box 197, Folder 5)
    - Lorna Gladstone, undated (Box unboxed)
      34 minutes, videocassette tape
  - Subseries 10.3: Artifacts, 1990s
    - University Center celebration scissors, 1993 April 23 (Box 198, Folder 1)
    - Think MasonLink and Xlibris buttons, 1990s (Box 198, Folder 2)
      Five buttons
- Series 11: Oversize 1984-2003
  This series consists of exhibit related material.
  - Fall for the book festival poster, 1999 September 23-25 (Box 199)
    Two posters
  - Millionth volume exhibit display texts, images, and notes, 2003 (Box 199)
  - Black history month exhibit, 1986 (Box 200, Folder 1)
    Photographs and display materials
  - Photo-etching exhibit "Prologue to Glory", 1990-1991 (Box 200, Folder 2)
  - Eleanor Roosevelt, friend of the Federal Theatre Project exhibit, 1984 October-December (Box 200, Folder 3)
  - Haight exhibit display texts, 1991 September-1992 February (Box 201, Folder 1)
  - Geothe-Schiller exhibit display materials, Faust notes, undated (Box 201, Folder 2)
  - Geothe-Schiller exhibit display materials, undated (Box 201, Folder 3)
  - Geothe-Schiller exhibit display materials, undated (Box 201, Folder 4)
  - Geothe-Schiller exhibit display materials, undated (Box 201, Folder 5)
  - Geothe-Schiller exhibit display materials, undated (Box 202)
    Small display texts
  - Geothe-Schiller exhibit display materials, undated (Box 203, Folder 1)
  - Geothe-Schiller exhibit display materials, undated (Box 203, Folder 2)
  - Geothe-Schiller exhibit display materials, undated (Box 203, Folder 3)